<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<ArrayOfExercise xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Sun Salutations
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Stand with feet together at front of mat, palms together at chest. Inhale, reaching arms up and into a slight back bend. Exhale, open arms and swan dive forward, bending over legs. Place hands on floor next to feet. Inhale and raise torso up into flat back. Hold for beat, exhale forward, placing hands on either side of feet. Gently step or jump back into Chaturanga (bottom of push-up position). Inhale, pulling torso forward and up into Downward Dog pose. Exhale, pushing up hips and torso into Downward Dog pose. From Downward Dog, inhale, bending knees and looking between hands, and hop feet forward to hands. Keeping hands on floor, straighten legs. Keeping back and legs strong, inhale into reverse swan dive, ending with fingers skyward and slight back bend. Exhale to Namaste. Repeat.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            3 reps
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Neck Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Reach arm behind body (above waist) and grab wrist of that arm with other hand. Pull on arm while tilting head in opposite direction of arm you're pulling. Repeat on other side.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Back up the Car
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Place arms straight out in front of you at shoulder height. Keep arms stable and turn head slowly to look over left shoulder. Repeat on other side.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Head Roll
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Stand tall with arms at sides reaching to floor. Roll head from right shoulder down to left shoulder and back.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            6 reps
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Expand, Contract Back-Chest-Shoulder Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            With a wide-foot stance, inhale arms up, reaching tall. Then release arms downward, expanding the chest and reaching elbows behind you. Arms should be wide, fingers flexed.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Topas Shoulder Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            In Horse Stance, start with hands in Prayer position at chest. Inhale and open arms out straight to sides, palms up, thumbs pointing behind you. Exhale back to Prayer position.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            3 reps
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Wrist-Forearm Flex Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            While on hands and knees, point fingers out away from body. Lean slowly side to side 10 times, feeling the stretch. From same position, place palms flat on floor with fingers pointing backward towards knees. Slowly lean back until stretch is felt. Hold for 10 seconds.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            10 reps, then hold for 20 seconds
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Dreya Forearm Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Start with arms extended out in front at shoulder height, palms up, fingers spread. Bend elbows, pulling hands in towards chest. Hold tension in hands and forearms as if pulling hands through wet cement. Finish by extending arms with fingers pointing downward and underside of forearms skyward.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            2 reps
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Arm Circles
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Extend arms straight out at sides, fingers towards ceiling. Move arms in small circles. Do 20 seconds clockwise and 20 seconds counterclockwise. Then position fingers down and repeat clockwise and counterclockwise movements for same amount of time.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Shoulder-Triceps Combo Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Extend left arm straight out. Grab upper left arm above elbow with right hand. Pull arm across body until you feel stretch in the shoulder. Hold for 10 seconds. Then raise bent arm overhead and with opposite hand grab elbow and pull arm back behind head and hold for 10 seconds. Repeat on other side.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Ballistic Stretches
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Huggers - Swing arms like giving yourself a hug, alternating arm position. Do for 20 seconds. Reachers - Standing with good posture, reach both arms up high and swing them back behind you as far as you can. Swimmers - One arm at a time, simulate craw stroke 10 seconds, then backstroke 10 seconds. Alternate arms.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            20 reps of each
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Standing Side Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Standing with feet together, place left arm alongside body and lift right arm overhead with palm facing floor. Open right side of rib cage. Repeat on other side.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Roller
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Lying on back, pull knees into chest by wrapping arms around legs. Tuck chin into chest and slowly roll back and forth, massaging the spine.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            20 reps
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Plough
        </Name>
        <Description>
            From Shoulder Stand, drop straight legs overhead until feet touch the floor. Then clasp hands and lay arms straight out on floor behind you. You may support yourself by placing hands on hips, using elbows for stabilization.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Seated Spinal Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            In seated position, pull right heel into left buttock and let knee drop to floor. Place left foot on floor, on right side of right knee. Reach right hand skyward and place left hand on floor directly behind you. Twist torso to left and drop right elbow to side of left thigh. On exhale, twist torso and head to left, while driving right elbow into thigh, keeping fingers skyward.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            5 reps each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Cat Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            On hands and knees, place hands directly beneath shoulders and knees directly under hips. Round back while exhaling and drop chin to chest. Reverse move, inhaling while arching back and lifting head.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            5 reps
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Glute Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Lying on back and pulling knee inward, place right ankle on left thigh. Reach right arm between right and left thigh. Reach left arm on outside of left thigh. Clasp hands around left shin. Lie back and pull knee in towards shoulder. Repeat on other side. To intensify: Straighten leg.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Wide-Feet Forward Hamstring Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            With feet wider than shoulder width, reach arms skyward, bending forward at waist. Hang forward with legs straight. Fold arms and rest head on them or just hang arms straight down.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Side Twist
        </Name>
        <Description>
            From Forward Fold, place right hand on floor below face and reach left arm up. Repeat on other side.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Camel
        </Name>
        <Description>
            While on knees, tilt pelvis forward and chest upward. Place hands on lower back while tucking chin to chest. One hand at a time, reach down and grab heel or bottom of foot. Then gently and slowly tilt head back. Note: Come out of this pose as slowly and gently as you went into it.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Cat Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            On hands and knees, place hands directly beneath shoulders and knees directly under hips. Round back while exhaling and drop chin to chest. Reverse move, inhaling while arching back and lifting head.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            1 rep
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Back Hero
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Kneel with knees and feet slightly wider than hips. Slowly lie backward, sitting between feet. Support body on elbows or lie all the way back. Come out of this pose as slowly and gently as you went into it.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Kenpo Quad Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Start on hands and knees. Pull right knee up and between hands. Turn outer ankle out towards floor and sit on ankle. Push left knee back away from body and grab left ankle with left hand, pulling back towards buttocks. Repeat on other side.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Bow
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Lying on stomach, bend knees, reach back behind body, and grab ankles. Arch back, lifting knees and chest off floor. Increase stretch and height by pushing feet against hands for added lift.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Low Squat
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Stand with feet shoulder-width apart or narrower, toes out. Squat down as low as possible, keeping chest and head up. Place hands in Prayer position. Use elbows to press against inner thighs to open hips. Gently rock back and forth.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Frog
        </Name>
        <Description>
            On hands and knees, spread legs wide, keeping lower legs parallel position. Lower upper body down towards floor while gently pressing hips backward. Keep legs and hips at 45-degree angle. Modify intensity by resting on forearms.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Seated Single-Leg Hamstring Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Extend right leg out in front of body with foot flexed. Bend left leg and turn knee outward, placing left foot on right inner thigh. Reach arm up overhead then bend at waist, collapsing torso over right leg. Repeat on other side. Always keep upper body relaxed, holding stretch for 45 seconds on each side. If needed, place yoga block at foot and reach around it for added stretch.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Seated Two-Leg Hamstring Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            From seated position, straighten both legs for two-legged forward bend and hold stretch. Grab as low as possible on the leg or wrap towel around foot to assist stretch. If needed, place yoga block at foot and reach around it for added stretch.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Split-Leg Hamstring Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Standing with feet together, take large step forward with right leg, keeping heels aligned. Turn left foot out, with arms reaching skyward. Exhale forward over right leg. Repeat on other side.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Toe Flexor
        </Name>
        <Description>
            While standing, straighten right leg at comfortable height. Point and flex foot 8 times, then circle foot inward 8 times, then outward 8 times. Repeat on opposite side.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            8 reps of each per side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Downward Dog with Calf Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            In Downward Dog position, separate feet hip-distance apart. Slowly alternate bending one knee while straightening other leg and driving heel into ground. Switch.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Upward Dog with Ankle Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            From Upward Dog position, keep knees off floor. Rest body weight on top of feet, stretching ankles.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Childs Pose with Right and Left Side Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Sitting on knees, fold body over legs and relax head and arms on floor. Stretch to right, then left by placing one hand over the other, then back to center. Relax arms alongside body, palms up.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            Hold for 30 seconds
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
</ArrayOfExercise>
