<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<ArrayOfExercise xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Sun Salutations
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Stand with feet together at front of mat, palms together at chest. Inhale, reaching arms up and into a slight back bend. Exhale, open arms and swan dive forward, bending over legs. Place hands on floor next to feet. Inhale and raise torso up into flat back. Hold for beat, exhale forward, placing hands on either side of feet. Gently step or jump back into Chaturanga (bottom of push-up position). Inhale, pulling torso forward and up into Downward Dog pose. Exhale, pushing up hips and torso into Downward Dog pose. From Downward Dog, inhale, bending knees and looking between hands, and hop feet forward to hands. Keeping hands on floor, straighten legs. Keeping back and legs strong, inhale into reverse swan dive, ending with fingers skyward and slight back bend. Exhale to Namaste. Repeat.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            5 reps
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Runner's Pose
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Bend over with legs split in a low forward lunge, front leg bent at 90 degrees. Knee should be over the ankle and back leg straight on the ball of foot. Fingertips barely touching the floor on either side of front foot. Lower torso towards floor and place both hands beside the instep of front foot or on the lower leg. Perform Vinyasa and repeat sequence on opposite side. To intensify: Deepen lunge and lower torso until elbows rest on floor.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Warrior One
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Same as Crescent Pose, except place heel on floor. Perform Vinyasa. To intensify: Deepen lunge and bring biceps close to ears during upward reach. Repeat on opposite side after Vinyasa.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Warrior Two
        </Name>
        <Description>
            From Warrior One position, extend front arm forward and rear arm backward. Arms should be parallel to the floor. Be sure hips and shoulders are in alignment. Repeat on opposite side after Vinyasa. To intensify: Deepen lunge and work on opening hips.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Reverse Warrior
        </Name>
        <Description>
            From Warrior Two position, bend torso back towards rear leg, gently placing hand on straight back leg. Opposite arm, while turning palm up, reaches and extends overhead towards back wall. Repeat on opposite side after Vinyasa. To intensify: Deepen lunge and extend reach without resting hand on back leg.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Triangle Pose to Twisting Triangle
        </Name>
        <Description>
            From Reverse Warrior, straighten front leg, go to Warrior Two, and reach forward with front hand. Kick back hip out and lower front hand towards floor on inside or outside of front leg while raising opposite hand skyward. Look to skyward hand. Do a Vinyasa, then repeat sequence on opposite side.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Warrior Three
        </Name>
        <Description>
            From Crescent Pose, lunge forward, shifting weight onto front leg and lifting back leg in line with torso. Straighten standing leg and reach arms straight ahead, parallel to torso and back leg.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Half Moon to Twisting Half Moon
        </Name>
        <Description>
            From Standing Splits (if standing on right leg), reach right hand forward near pinkie toe, simultaneously opening torso and lifting other arm skyward. Eyes are focused on skyward hand. Use yoga block if necessary. Switch hands and reach opposite arm skyward. Repeat on opposite side after Vinyasa. Perform your last Vinyasa for this workout.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Tree
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Stand on one leg, place foot on other leg on inside of thigh. Rotate knee of non-weight-bearing leg to side. Hold hands in Prayer position, then reach arms overhead. Repeat on opposite side.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Royal Dancer
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Stand on right leg with left hand holding inside of left ankle. Push left foot out against hand, lifting leg. Tilt at waist while simultaneously raising right arm out in front of body. Keep palm skyward. Repeat on opposite side. To intensify: Increase leg left and lean forward.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Seated Spinal Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Seated position, pull right heel into left buttock and let knees drop to floor. Place left foot on floor on right side of right knee. Reach right hand skyward, place left hand on floor directly behind you. Twist torso to left and drop right elbow to the side of left thigh. On exhale, twist torso and head to left, while driving right elbow into thigh, keeping fingers skyward. Make sure head is up.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            5 reps per side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Cat Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            On hands and knees with hands directly beneath shoulders and knees directly under hips, round back while exhaling and drip chin to chest. Reverse move, inhaling while arching back and lifting head.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            9 reps
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Frog
        </Name>
        <Description>
            On hands and knees, spread legs wide, keeping lower legs in parallel position (90 degrees at hips and knees). Lower upper body towards floor while gently pressing hips backward. Modify intensify by resting on forearms. To intensify: Pelvis on floor. Forget it, guys.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Bridge or Wheel
        </Name>
        <Description>
            While lying on your back, bend your knees, placing your feet on floor hip-distance apart with heels close to buttocks. Tilt pelvis skyward while clasping hands and straightening arms beneath you. To intensify: From starting Bridge Pose, place hands on floor on each side of head (fingers towards shoulders) and begin to straighten arms and legs into back bend. To really intensify, while in Wheel, straighten arms and raise one leg to sky.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Plough
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Roll onto upper back, raising hips, drop feet to the floor. Final move of sequence is bending knees to ears. Come out of this pose by gently unrolling from top of spine to lower spine.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Table
        </Name>
        <Description>
            From a seated position, place palms on floor beneath shoulders, fingers facing forward. Bend knees with feet on floor, hip-width apart. Lift your body and drive pelvis skyward. Keep elbows locked, torso parallel to the floor and knees over ankles. Keep chin tucked into chest. To intensify: Keeping spine aligned, tilt head back and look straight up.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Cobbler Pose
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Seated with soles together and knees out to sides, grasp feet in close to hips. Pull feet in, stretching up with straight back (use towel under feet to alleviate ankle pain). Do 30 seconds with a flat back 30 seconds reaching arms forward. To intensify: Keep back straight while folding forward.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            One-Legged Hamstring Stretch into Two-Legged Hamstring Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Seated, extend right leg and bend the left knee out to the side, foot on inner thigh. Bend torso from hips over extended leg and clasp foot with both hands. Repeat on other side. Part 2: Straighten both legs for Two-Legged Forward Bend and repeat stretch. Grab as low as possible on the leg or wrap towel around foot to assist stretch. To intensify: Use yoga block for extended reach
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side, then 30 seconds
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Side Twist
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Lie on back, bend right knee, and pull heel into buttocks. Place left hand on outside of right knee and pull across body towards floor while looking right. Repeat on other side. To intensify: Keep knee and opposite hand on floor.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Glute Stretch
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Lying on back and pulling knee inward, place right ankle on left thigh. Reach right arm between right and left thigh. Reach left arm on outside of left thigh. Clasp hands around left shin. Lie back and pull left knee in towards shoulder. Repeat on other side.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds each side
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
    <Exercise>
        <Name>
            Child's Pose
        </Name>
        <Description>
            Sitting on knees, fold body over legs and relax head and arms on floor. Relax arms alongside body, palms up or out front with palms down. To intensify: For added side stretch, while reaching overhead slide both hands to left, placing right hand over left. Repeat on other side with left hand over right.
        </Description>
        <Routine>
            30 seconds
        </Routine>
    </Exercise>
</ArrayOfExercise>
